[Looney Tunes fanfare playing]
["Slap That Bass" by
George and Ira Gershwin playing]
[people chanting]
Joker! Joker! Joker!
[loud cheering, whistling]
Mmm?
[grunts]
[loud crash]
- [grunting]
- [punches landing]
[hammering on door]
[gasps, shrieks]
[exclaiming dizzily]
Huh?
- [bone cracks]
- [yells]
[guttural growling]
[emcee] And now
without further ado... Joker!
[audience cheers]
["What the World Needs Now"
playing]
♪ What the world needs now ♪
- ♪ Is love, sweet love ♪
- [crowd laughing]
♪ It's the only thing ♪
♪ That there's just
Too little of ♪
♪ What the world needs now ♪
- ♪ Is love, sweet love ♪
- [crowd laughing]
♪ No, not just for some
But for everyone ♪
Tell me about it.
[people exclaiming]
♪ Lord, we don't need
Another mountain ♪
♪ There are mountains
And hillsides ♪
♪ Enough to climb ♪
♪ There are oceans and rivers ♪
[cheering]
♪ Enough to cross ♪
♪ Enough to last
'til the end of time ♪
[humming cadence]
- ♪ What the world needs now ♪
- [laughter]
[both] ♪ Is love, sweet love ♪
♪ It's the only thing
That there's ♪
- ♪ Just too little of ♪
♪ What the world needs now
Is love, sweet love ♪
- [feedback squeals]
- [audience cheers]
[grunting]
Knock, knock.
[Joker screaming]
[curtain pulleys squeaking]
[song ends]
[man whistling "When the Saints
Go Marching In"]
[door locks clanking]
[lights buzzing]
[faint, echoing shouts]
[whistling continues]
Morning, sir.
Nothing good about it.
Get up!
Let's go, get up.
[head guard] Let's go boys.
Let's get this show on the road.
[guard 2] Come on! Come on!
[guard 3]
Come on, get out of bed.
Let's go, get up.
Clean this fucking mess up.
[guard 4]
Hey, Jackie, I need a hand.
[metal rattling]
- Put some clothes on.
- [Jackie whistling]
[guard 3] Diaz, what the fuck?
[inmates moaning, chattering]
- [keys jingle]
- [lock clicking]
[guard 2]
You got a joke for me today?
[man] Move!
[guard 2] All right, come on,
let's go, guys.
Move your fucking ass. Move.
[guard 3]
Don't test me, Walters.
[guard] Come on, boys.
[guard 2] Get him on the ground.
[guard 4]
Move your fucking ass, Bullock.
[Bullock] Fuck you!
[heavy struggling]
[Bullock]
Get the fuck out my cell.
- [can clattering]
- [men grunting]
[Bullock] Leave me alone.
Hey, Arthur, you feelin'
crazy today or what?
[men fighting]
[Bullock]
I don't wanna come out today.
[Jackie]
Take him down to F Ward.
[Bullock]
I don't wanna come out today.
You got a big day today.
You better put on a happy face.
[Bullock] Get the fuck off me.
[guard]
Let's not do this again, Beanie.
[faint shouts, chatter]
[man] Shut up!
[Jackie] Let's go, Arthur.
[guard 2] Come on, Fleck.
Don't need your fancy lawyer
blaming me if you're late.
She knows how much you like me, right?
Hey, Fleck,
you got a joke for us today?
[Jackie] Yeah,
it's been a while, hasn't it?
[door lock buzzing]
[Jackie whistling "When
the Saints Go Marching In"]
Move.
[inmate shuddering]
[faint shouts and yelling]
[guard] Right on the line.
Let's go!
[Jackie] Back the fuck up, Ken.
[guard 2] Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Go on, front of the line.
[Jackie]
Fleck. Fleck's next, my dear.
[guard] Hey, stay in line.
[young man] Yeah, you heard him.
[guard] Hey, hey, hey, back up.
[guard shouting in pain]
[guard] Freak bit me!
[overlapping shouts]
Go.
[guard] All that kid's done
since he got here
is fucking smile.
And today, all of a sudden,
he bites Moran?
[Jackie]
It's because nobody likes Moran.
He was at Gotham State
for, like, eight years
before he got here,
and he's still a fucking temp.
[Jackie and guard laughing]
Hey, Fleck,
you got a joke for us today?
[guard] I already asked him.
[Jackie] I got a joke for ya.
This guy's dog dies, right?
And he really loved this dog.
So, he goes down to the church,
and he asks Father Mulcahy
if he'd perform
a funeral for him. Right?
And Mulcahy says, "Oh, no.
[stammering] I'm sorry my son,
we can't have a service
for an animal in our church.
Uh, but, I bet if you go down
- to the veterinarian in town..."
- [barber] Fuck.
[Jackie] "...he can do it
for you. You see?"
[barber] Goddamn it, Arthur.
[Jackie] Uh, so the guy says,
"Oh, thanks very much, Father."
And he says,
"Do you think two grand
would be enough
to cover the service?"
Father Mulcahy looks at him...
"Why didn't you tell me
the dog was Catholic?"
[all laughing]
[razor clattering]
[Jackie laughing] Eh?
Clean yourself up.
You like that one, Arthur?
Let's go. [chuckling]
[high voice]
"Why didn't you tell me
the dog was a Catholic?"
[all laughing]
[thunder rumbling]
[sighing]
[faint chatter over P.A.]
[Jackie] Look around, Arthur.
This is how
the other half lives.
[bearded guard]
Could have been all yours
if you hadn't killed
five people.
[Jackie chuckles]
[bearded guard]
One live on national TV.
[chorus] ♪ When you close your
Earthly story... ♪
[older guard]
What the fuck is this shit?
♪ Will you join them
In their bliss ♪
- [piano playing along]
- ♪ Will the circle
Be unbroken ♪
[Jackie] Move, will ya? Moron.
[woman] Hey!
Come on. You fucking lunatic.
[Jackie laughing]
[singing continues]
Jesus Christ, you couldn't
get him a fucking umbrella?
Aw, come on, counselor,
you know we can't
give these boys umbrellas.
It's for their own good.
Oh, don't give me your shit.
He's soaking wet.
Well, those are the rules,
counselor,
but I'll break them
if you ask me.
I bet you would.
[Jackie chuckles] Mm-hm.
Oh, you're welcome, by the way,
for getting him
all cleaned up for you.
[guards cracking up]
Sit down.
Here, Arthur.
[guards chattering faintly]
Today,
we're meeting with Dr. Beatty.
Remember her?
She's gonna be
videotaping you this time,
so we can show it at your
competency hearing next week.
- [guards chuckling faintly]
- And if they find you competent,
and they will, they always do,
then we're going to trial.
You need to be in an actual
hospital with actual doctors.
Not this
Department of Corrections...
bullshit with these thugs.
Dr. Beatty thinks
that with everything
that happened to you
in your childhood,
it caused a split...
- this fragmentation in you...
- [thunder rumbling]
...to help you cope
with your pain.
She believes you have another
person living inside of you.
And it was this other person
who committed those crimes.
Do you understand
what that means, Arthur?
[video recorder humming softly]
[Dr. Beatty] I'll be asking you
a few questions today, Arthur,
okay?
Maybe you don't remember
some things?
Or you're confused
about what you did?
I'm here to help you
try and sort out what happened.
[tape recorder clicks]
Arthur, I'm not here
only to help with your defense.
I'm here for you.
But for me to do my job,
I need you to be
candid with me.
Does that make sense?
Can I have a cigarette?
[Dr. Beatty] Of course you can.
Let's start
with the first incident, okay?
The three men who accosted you
on the subway, who bullied you,
did it feel like they
triggered something painful?
From your past? Your childhood?
Do you remember
any of what happened?
Did you... black out?
See bright lights?
[Arthur] Mm...
Okay.
How about Murray Franklin?
What, if anything, do you
remember about that night?
The music.
[Dr. Beatty] That's good.
Arthur, that is good.
Can I tell you what I remember
about that night?
I remember you came out
dressed as Joker.
And I remember Joker
was dancing to that music.
Right?
I really liked his band.
My mom and I u-- used
to watch the show together.
[Dr. Beatty] She liked
Murray Franklin as well?
[in falsetto voice]
"He's so handsome.
Look at those
sparkling white teeth."
Is that your mother's voice?
[Arthur] Mm.
Do you often hear her voice
in your head?
[inhaling]
[sighing] All the time.
[thunder rumbles faintly]
[chuckles weakly]
[Dr. Beatty] Did it change
at all after she died?
What does that mean?
Did you...
this other part of you...
Joker...
Did it come out more
after she died?
You lived together, right?
In a one-bedroom apartment?
[cigarette crackling faintly]
Maybe I could talk to Joker
about it.
Would he like to talk to me?
[trumpet playing "When
the Saints Go Marching In"]
[overlapping chatter]
[young man] Hey, Arthur.
Arthur.
[younger guard] I mean,
he'll do anything. Anything.
The guards said you wanted
to show me how to kiss.
But they said Joker's
a really good kisser.
Nobody's ever gave me
a kiss before.
[bearded guard] Twenty bucks
says he chokes him.
[guards exclaiming, laughing]
[younger guard] There you go.
[bearded guard]
Ricky don't know what hit him.
[Jackie]
There was no hesitation.
[younger guard]
Yeah, yeah. [laughs]
[Jackie] Kinda like...
I gotta be honest with you,
Arthur.
I wouldn't have took you
for a hopeless romantic.
Can I have a cigarette?
Why not.
Oh, no, no, no.
What are you doing?
He doesn't get a cigarette
unless he tells a joke.
No, come on. He still
makes us laugh, doesn't he?
[younger guard scoffs] Barely.
[Jackie] Hey.
Remember that music class
we saw?
The other day? B Ward?
Remember, with all the singing?
I got you in.
We're going next week.
[younger guard] Bullshit.
- The fuck you do that for?
- Eh, eh. No, no.
Went and saw Kellerman,
I said...
you've been good.
You deserve it.
[younger guard laughs]
The hell is he thinking?
Yeah.
He knows he can get
some good press for it.
Plus, I told him
I'd go along with him.
[younger guard]
Oh, ho, there it is.
- That explains it.
- [chuckles]
- [bell clanging]
- [yard guard] Count! Let's go.
Line up by two.
Ricky. Come on, Romeo,
line 'em up.
[Ricky] Let's go. Twos.
Line up by twos.
[younger guard]
Come on, let's go.
Are you being serious?
[Jackie] I am being serious.
On the Bible.
Wasn't that hard, either.
Ever since they made
that TV movie about you,
everybody still thinks
you're a star.
How about you, Arthur?
Do you still think
you're a star?
I bet you do, don't you?
["That's Life"
by Frank Sinatra playing]
[Jackie] ♪ I said that's life ♪
All right, Arthur.
Come on, let's go.
[Jackie] ♪ That's what
All the people say ♪
- [door thuds]
- [keys jingling]
[exhales]
[Jackie whistling "When
the Saints Go Marching In"]
[older guard] Get out of bed.
[bearded guard]
Anderson, come on, let's go.
[inmates chattering, yelling]
[bearded guard]
Clifford, what the fuck.
[Jackie]
Let's go, boys, it's showtime.
Wakey-wakey!
- [guard] Move. Let's go.
- [bearded guard] Get up.
[younger guard]
Hey, come on. Let's go.
[Jackie] Look at you, Arthur.
Shot out of a cannon
this morning.
[younger guard]
All right, move it!
Hope they'll let me sing.
♪ Oh when the saints
Go marchin' in ♪
[Jackie humming melody]
♪ I want to be in that number ♪
♪ When the saints
Go marchin' in ♪
[all] ♪ The sun is shining
Come on, get happy ♪
♪ The Lord is waiting
To take your hand ♪
♪ Sing hallelujah ♪
- ♪ Come on, get happy... ♪
- [Jackie clears throat]
- [singing dies down]
- Hold it, hold it. Hold it...
Group, I want you to welcome
Arthur Fleck.
Now, I know it's odd to have
an inmate from E Ward in here,
but I have been assured
he's been a model patient
without any incidents.
I know this might feel strange,
Mr. Fleck, a new environment.
You see, we use music
in this class to make us whole,
to balance
the conflicting forces, the...
...the fractures
within ourselves.
All I ask is that you sing,
if and when
you're ready to sing.
[piano resumes playing]
Okay, let's go.
[all] ♪ Forget your troubles
Come on, get happy ♪
♪ You better chase
All your cares away ♪
♪ Sing hallelujah
Come on, get happy ♪
[teacher]
How about this one? Try this.
No, no, no, I can't really.
Look, I don't know it.
[teacher] Okay. Um...
Oh, this one.
[whispers] Is it really you?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- [teacher] Yeah? Great.
I'll give that one a go.
Yeah, yeah, C.
[piano plays a "C" chord]
♪ I got the world on a string
Sitting on a rainbow ♪
[teacher] Excellent. That's it.
♪ Got the string
Around my finger ♪
♪ What a world, what a life
I'm in love ♪
My name's Lee.
Hi.
I'm Arthur.
[whispers] I know.
♪ I've got a song that I sing ♪
[teacher chuckles]
♪ I can make the rain go ♪
So, what's a nice guy like you
doing in a place like this?
I killed five people.
One live on national television.
What about you?
I set fire to my parents'
apartment building.
[Jackie continues singing,
indistinct]
Actually...
...it was six.
Nobody knows,
but also I killed my mother.
[chuckles lightly]
I should have done that.
My mother had me committed.
She says I'm psychotic.
You know, I must've watched
that TV movie
they made about you,
like, 20 times.
Yeah. Was it good?
They won't let me watch it.
It was good.
It was really good.
I grew up
in the same neighborhood.
Me and my friends
used to take that staircase
to school every day.
My parents didn't
give a fuck about me either.
My father beat the shit
out of me.
Well, guess what?
"Knock, knock."
"Sorry, kid, your dad
was killed in a car accident."
[sharp, wheezy laugh]
Sorry. That's not funny.
[stifling laughter]
[both laughing]
If only those friends
could see me now.
When I first saw Joker,
when I saw you
on Murray Franklin,
the whole time I was watching,
I kept thinking,
"I hope this guy
blows his brains out."
And then you did.
And for once in my life,
I didn't feel so alone anymore.
♪ Forget your troubles
Come on, get happy ♪
♪ You better chase
All your cares away ♪
♪ Sing hallelujah
Come on, get happy ♪
[both] ♪ Get ready
For the judgement day ♪
[Jackie whistles sharply]
[Lee] ♪ The sun is shining
Come on, get happy ♪
[Lee laughs giddily]
♪ The Lord is waiting
To take your hand ♪
♪ Sing hallelujah
Come on, get happy ♪
Hey, Jackie.
You wanna know
what I regret most
from being on
The Murray Franklin Show?
What's that?
That I didn't shoot first and
let him ask me questions later.
[Jackie chuckles]
That a joke, Arthur?
- Yeah.
- [laughs]
All it took was you
getting a little old fashioned.
[Jackie laughs]
Thanks, pal.
[Jackie]
Let's get your medication.
Not guilty
by reason of insanity
makes no sense in this case.
He murdered
five innocent people.
- His depraved
acts of violence...
- [bearded guard] Hey, Fleck.
- You're on the news.
- ...admired by his followers,
not only in our city,
but all over the country.
Vandalism, arson...
The judge says
you're competent to stand trial.
I fucking knew it.
And they are still willing
to commit acts of violence
in his name.
Now, these people,
they believe Arthur Fleck
to be some kind of... martyr.
- [inmates murmuring]
- Well, he's not.
Arthur Fleck is a monster,
who knew exactly
what he was doing.
- [inmate] Yep.
- [inmate 2] Hear, hear.
And our office will be
seeking the death penalty.
Thank you, we'll be taking
no questions today.
- [inmate 3] Shit, bro.
- [inmates chattering]
You hear that, Fleck?
The death penalty.
They're gonna fry you, Artie.
How does that feel?
[faint chatter on television]
[Arthur]
♪ For once in my life ♪
♪ I have someone who needs me ♪
♪ Someone I've needed so long ♪
♪ For once, unafraid ♪
♪ I can go
Where life leads me ♪
♪ Somehow I know
I'll be strong ♪
♪ For once I can touch what
My heart used to dream of ♪
♪ Long before I knew ♪
♪ Someone warm like you ♪
[inmates chatter excitedly]
♪ Would make my dreams
Come true ♪
♪ For once in my life
I won't let sorrow hurt me ♪
♪ Not like
It's hurt me before ♪
♪ For once, I have someone
I know won't desert me ♪
♪ And I'm not alone anymore ♪
[encouraging chatter]
♪ For once I can say ♪
♪ "This is mine
You can't take it" ♪
Tell 'em!
♪ As long as I know
I've got love, I can make it ♪
♪ For once in my life
I've got someone who needs me ♪
[Bullock] Go, Arthur.
[upbeat, jazzy music swells]
[Bullock] Go, man. [laughs]
[Arthur whoops]
♪ For once I can say ♪
♪ "This is mine
You can't take it" ♪
♪ Long as I know I've got love
I can make it ♪
♪ For once in my life
I've got someone ♪
♪ For once in my life ♪
[Ricky] Answer him, Arthur.
How's it make you feel?
You scared?
[inmate] Yeah, tell 'em!
[faint chatter from television]
[light chatter, laughter]
[Arthur chuckles lightly]
[thunder crashing]
[Arthur laughing deeply]
[continues laughing]
[laughter fades]
[lawyer] No, you cannot give
any statements to the press,
even if Kellerman asked you to.
You know they've been
out there all week.
To see me.
They wanna talk to me.
[whispers] Hey, Fleck.
- I told you before, I set up...
- Could you sign my book?
...an exclusive interview
next month, right before trial.
Okay, but Kellerman asked me
to make a statement now.
He's letting me go
to this movie tonight.
- You know, like a normal person.
- What movie?
What are you talking about?
Come on, Arthur.
Okay. Um...
- Yeah, I'm sorry. I have to go.
- Arthur, I told you--
Okay, let's move it.
Hang on, Jackie.
He's signing my book.
[sighs] Make it quick, Arthur.
I don't want to miss
the beginning.
[whispers] Gonna be worth
a fortune when they fry his ass.
[Jackie] Easy, now.
[pen scribbling]
- [pen drops]
- [book slams]
[Jackie] Let's go.
[Jeffrey Cordova on screen]
Musical. Musical.
I'm sick of these
artificial barriers
between the musical
and the drama.
[Tony Hunter] Well, then you
certainly don't need me.
[inmate coughing]
Yes, we do.
Because you can be
greater than you ever were.
We are going to make you
explode on the theater scene
like a sky rocket.
Not just the old trademark
with the top hat, tie
and tails, but a great artist
- at the peak of his powers.
- Let's get outta here.
The new Tony Hunter.
- Tony Hunter, 1953.
- I can't.
They'll shoot me.
Come on. You already know
how this is gonna end.
- Everything's gonna work out.
- Shhh...
Well, what do you think I am?
What do you think they are?
What do you think
the theater is?
It's all entertainment.
Believe me,
there is no difference
between the magic rhythms
of Bill Robinson's
immortal feet and--
[Tony Hunter]
You said that before.
- [laughter]
- All right, all right.
Well,
what did Bill Robinson do?
He danced on the stairs,
didn't he?
Now, I happened to play Oedipus
the King on the same stairs.
What's the difference?
We're all theater.
Show me the lowest
red nose comic in burlesque,
and I'll show you
an entertainer.
We're all enter--[yells]
You're gonna miss the song.
♪ Everything
That happens in life ♪
- [laughs]
- ♪ Can happen in a show ♪
♪ You can make 'em laugh
You can make 'em cry ♪
♪ Anything
Anything can go ♪
[up-tempo music
playing on screen]
♪ The clown
With his pants falling down ♪
♪ Or the dance
That's a dream of romance ♪
♪ Or the scene
Where the villain is mean ♪
♪ That's entertainment ♪
♪ The lights
On the lady in tights ♪
♪ Or the bride
With the guy on the side ♪
♪ Or the ball
Where she gives him her all ♪
[all] ♪ That's entertainment ♪
- Now that I understand.
- [Lily Marton]
♪ The plot can be hot ♪
♪ Simply teeming with sex ♪
[Lester Marton]
♪ A gay divorcée
Who is after her ex ♪
[Tony Hunter]
♪ It could be Oedipus Rex ♪
♪ Where a chap
Kills his father ♪
- ♪ And causes a lot of bother ♪
- [flames crackling]
[woman] Fire!
[all shouting, screaming]
[Jackie] Don't panic.
[bearded guard]
Easy, easy. Calm down.
- [all clamoring]
- [alarm bell clanging]
[Jackie] Arthur, let's go.
Arthur, right now!
[sounds fade]
[bearded guard, faintly]
Slow down, one at a time.
[Lee]
♪ If they could see me now ♪
♪ That little gang of mine ♪
[bearded guard]
Come on, let's go. Go!
♪ I'm looking at your smile
And it's a healthy sight ♪
[flames roaring]
♪ I'd like those stumblebums
To see for a fact ♪
♪ The kind of top-drawer ♪
- ♪ First-rate chum I attract ♪
- [both laughing]
[sirens wailing]
[panting]
Did... Did you do that?
I told you
I wanted to get outta there.
Are you crazy?
♪ All I can say is "Wow"
Just look at where I am ♪
♪ Tonight, I landed, pow
Right in a pot of jam ♪
♪ What a setup, holy cow
They'll never believe it ♪
♪ If my friends
Could see me... ♪
[dogs barking]
[laughing] Oh, fuck.
- [horn blares]
- [sirens wailing]
Come on, this way.
- They're coming.
- [officer] Come on, let's go.
See, isn't this more fun
than a movie?
♪ If they could see me now
That little dusty group ♪
♪ Traipsing around this
Million-dollar chicken coop ♪
♪ I'm rubbing elbows
With the cream of the crop ♪
♪ Whoever said ♪
♪ There ain't no room
At the top ♪
- Whoo!
- [sirens wailing]
[horn honking]
[indistinct chatter, shouts]
Let's go.
♪ To think this famous man
Which I must say is he ♪
♪ Should pick an unknown gal
Which there's no doubt is me ♪
♪ What a step up, wow, holy cow
They'll never believe it ♪
♪ If my friends could see me ♪
- ♪ If my friends could see me ♪
- ♪ Could see me ♪
- ♪ If they all could... ♪
- ♪ If they could see me ♪
♪ ...see me now ♪
Get the fuck off me!
[Arthur laughing]
[Lee] You fucker!
[screams]
[Arthur laughing uncontrollably]
[bearded guard]
Keep laughing, asshole.
[Arthur keeps laughing]
[bearded guard]
Last one down on the left.
[Jackie] You wanna play
games on my watch, Arthur?
Two weeks in the hole.
- [Arthur cackling]
- [guard grunts]
[door latches, locks]
[bearded guard] Enjoy your stay.
[laughing deeply]
[gagging, choking]
[female voice vocalizing]
[piano playing waltz]
♪ Take my hand
Stay here my friend ♪
♪ I'll find my way
Back to you ♪
♪ Here and now
I know somehow ♪
♪ We tell a story that's true ♪
♪ In our minds
We'd be just fine ♪
♪ If it were only us two ♪
♪ They might
Say that we're crazy ♪
♪ But I'm just
In love with you ♪
[Lee] There's my guy.
[exhales softly]
[whispers] Are you really here?
[Lee] Yeah.
One of the guards let me in.
I'd do anything for you.
But we don't have a lot of time.
Come here.
[Arthur] What?
[Lee] Come on. Can you get up?
Come into the light.
They're sending me home.
What? Why?
They're saying you're
a bad influence on me.
What?
This is gonna be good for us.
Now, I can be at your trial
every day.
I can see you every day
until you get out.
And then what?
We're gonna build a mountain.
Wait, wait.
[case rattling]
You brought make-up.
I want to see the real you.
Look what they did to you.
It's just us now.
You need to stop
taking your medication.
I already have.
[pants rustling]
[Arthur] Can you do it?
Yeah.
[Arthur breathing shakily]
[both panting]
What's he gonna ask me about?
Besides... you know.
Well, hopefully,
about your life in here,
and what the conditions
are really like in this place.
He might ask you about Lee.
She's been out there giving
a lot of interviews about you.
And about herself.
Good.
You know, I love her.
She gets me.
Two minutes. Paddy's ready.
Arthur.
This is a chance for you to show
a different side of yourself.
So the public can see
who you really are.
And I don't think
you should smoke.
I think it makes you
look cavalier.
Okay.
We need to use this time
to show people
that you're human.
They need to understand
you were sick. Delusional.
Mm-hm.
You're not Joker.
You're Arthur Fleck.
[lawyer] Hm?
Don't worry.
You're gonna be great.
[chuckles]
Arthur.
[chuckling] Are you okay? It's--
It's not too late to cancel.
[lighter clicks]
So, uh... you want me
to call you Arthur or The Joker?
Mr. Meyers,
you know we have an agreement.
You can't call him "Joker."
It's Arthur. Arthur Fleck.
- When you're ready, Paddy.
- [exhales]
She has to leave now.
You can watch
from behind the glass,
but you can't be in here.
[whispers] Just be yourself.
- We rolling?
- Rolling.
[Paddy clears throat]
[producer over radio]
Cameras up.
[beeps]
Two years ago,
the name Arthur Fleck
hit Gotham like a hurricane.
An unassuming part-time
party clown
and struggling stand-up comic,
Fleck committed
five horrific murders
in the span of just four weeks.
And now, with hundreds
already lining up to get a seat
at one of the first trials
ever broadcast live on TV,
Arthur Fleck, The Joker,
is sitting down
for his first interview
since that infamous night
on Murray Franklin.
And yes, we all know
how that turned out.
[sharp laugh]
- [Arthur clears throat]
- Arthur Fleck, welcome.
Hello.
Take me back to that night
onstage with Murray Franklin.
What was going
through your mind...
when you pulled out that gun
and blew his brains out?
Well, Paddy, um...
I was going through a lot
back then. Um...
I don't really remember much
from that night. I, uh...
blacked out,
I saw bright lights.
I was having a hard time
knowing the difference
between what was real or not.
[Paddy] Oh, please.
You did it on live TV, pal.
Doesn't get any more real
than that.
Paddy, all I remember
from that night
is I was gonna kill myself.
On television.
I thought Murray
was playing a part in my show.
But he was a bad actor.
So he got what he deserved.
Your last joke,
if we can call it a joke,
"You get
what you bleeping deserve."
That's what you said.
That's not fun,
that's not funny.
You're right, I...
I should have told a better one.
You're trying to be funny now?
No.
Do you deserve to die?
The DA is calling
for the death penalty.
You just said that you wanted
to kill yourself on TV.
So, tell us...
...you still wanna die?
Well, at the time, it certainly
seemed a lot easier than living.
Um, but that's...
that's not me anymore.
That's not...
That's not who I am.
That wasn't really you.
[stammering]
No, that's not right.
Let me get this straight.
- That's not what I meant.
- So your defense is,
"It was The Joker who did it."
- An insanity defense.
- Okay, I don't--
I don't know about a defense.
That this alternate personality,
this killer clown in you
killed Murray.
Who am I speaking to now?
Which one of you is here?
The poor, low IQ Arthur Fleck?
Or The Joker, who goaded
a bunch of no-good punks--
Do you really care?
You don't.
You're just like Murray.
You're just like everyone.
You want sensationalism.
You don't care about...
You just wanna talk
about my mistakes.
You wanna talk about the things
that I did in the past.
Not about who I am now.
Not how I'm different now.
That's what we should be
talking about, Paddy.
Okay, okay.
- We should take a break.
- We're not taking a break.
[Paddy] All right.
Okay, so, tell us...
what's changed, Arthur?
Well, I'll tell you
what's changed, Paddy.
I'm not alone anymore.
Right.
The girl who was singing.
The night you tried to escape.
[chuckles]
We weren't trying to escape.
Miss Harley Quinzel.
You two put on
quite a performance that night.
[Arthur] Aww...
She's really something,
isn't she?
You tell me.
I mean,
don't you think it's all...
...don't you think
it's a little too much?
A little much?
♪ She's a fool
And don't I know it ♪
♪ But a fool
Can have her charms ♪
♪ I'm in love ♪
♪ And don't I show it ♪
♪ Like a babe in arms ♪
♪ Love's the same old
Sad sensation ♪
♪ Lately
I've not slept a wink ♪
♪ Since this half-pint
Imitation ♪
♪ Put me on the blink ♪
♪ I'm wild again ♪
♪ Beguiled again ♪
♪ A simpering, whimpering
Child again ♪
♪ Bewitched ♪
♪ Bothered and bewildered ♪
♪ Am I ♪
♪ Lost my heart
But what of it ♪
[over television]
♪ She is cold, I agree ♪
♪ She can laugh
And I love it ♪
♪ Although the laugh's on me ♪
♪ I'll sing to her ♪
♪ Bring spring to her ♪
♪ And long for the day ♪
♪ When I cling to her ♪
[both] ♪ Bewitched ♪
♪ Bothered and bewildered ♪
- ♪ Am I ♪
- Excuse me. Yeah, thank you.
[Paddy] We'll be back
with more of Arthur Fleck
after a word from our sponsors.
[man on radio] The murder trial
of Arthur Fleck
will begin today.
Assistant DA, Harvey Dent,
is preparing
his opening remarks
in what some are calling,
"The Trial of the Century."
[woman on radio]
After months of protests,
police will be on high alert,
closing surrounding streets,
and setting up barricades
for crowds
that could reach
in the thousands.
[man] If you ask me,
this is what you get
when there's a complete
breakdown of social services.
And don't get me started
on this media frenzy.
All right, Denise,
you're on the air.
[Denise] Thank you for taking
my call. Enough is enough.
This idiot
doesn't deserve a trial.
He should be sent
straight to the chair.
An example should be made
out of him.
[indistinct radio chatter]
[siren whooping]
[laughing tensely]
[Arthur]
♪ When you're smiling ♪
[crowd clamoring]
♪ The whole world
Smiles with you ♪
♪ When you're laughing ♪
♪ Oh, when you're laughing ♪
♪ The sun comes
Shining through ♪
♪ But when you're crying ♪
♪ You bring out the rain ♪
♪ So stop your sighing ♪
♪ Be happy again ♪
♪ Keep on smiling ♪
♪ 'Cause when you're smiling ♪
♪ The whole world smiles ♪
♪ With you ♪
Coming in.
[guard] Okay. Showtime.
[swirling, excited chatter]
Shh! Shh! There he is.
[laughter]
[man on TV] Arthur Fleck...
Hey, shut the fuck up.
[man continues,
indistinct on television]
Arthur.
[bearded guard] Milligan.
[Milligan] Arthur.
[bearded guard]
I'll split your head open.
[crowd cheering]
[cameras clicking]
[cheering continues]
[Bullock] Yeah, Arthur.
[laughter, whistling]
[Bullock] He's looking good.
[bailiff] All rise.
This court is now in session.
The Honorable Judge
Herman Rothwax is presiding.
[door opens]
Good morning,
ladies and gentlemen.
Please be seated.
William,
please invite the jury in.
[door opens]
[judge]
Are you all right, Mr. Fleck?
Everything okay?
Yes, Your Majesty.
I'm just looking for someone.
- [feedback squeals]
- [laughter]
Please, Mr. Fleck, sit down.
I realize
there's a lot going on.
But this is still
a court of law.
Any and all outbursts
will not be tolerated.
And that applies
to everyone in this courtroom.
Sidney, please call the case.
The People
of the State of New York
versus Arthur Fleck.
Case number GC071963.
[Lee] ♪ Everything that
Happens in life ♪
♪ Can happen in a show ♪
♪ You can make 'em laugh ♪
♪ You can make 'em cry ♪
♪ Anything ♪
♪ Anything can go ♪
♪ The clown
With his pants falling down ♪
♪ Or the dance
That's the dream of romance ♪
♪ Or the scene
Where the villain is mean ♪
♪ That's entertainment ♪
♪ The lights
On the lady in tights ♪
♪ Or the bride
With the guy on the side ♪
♪ Or the ball
Where she gives it her all ♪
It's my view that there is
absolutely no evidence
that Arthur Fleck suffers from
multiple personality disorder.
Or that he ever behaved
in the role of "Joker,"
as a separate personality
dissociated from himself.
[Dent] Doctor, in your opinion,
concerning the work
you did on this case,
do you believe Mr. Fleck suffers
from a mental disease or defect?
[doctor] No. In my opinion,
he's not psychotic
or unable to test reality.
I think he was sane
when he committed these crimes.
In fact, I believe he fakes
his mental illness.
[people murmuring]
[judge] Quiet.
[gavel rapping]
And... if he's, uh...
...faking it, as you say,
then what is your opinion
on the defendant's
mental condition?
I believe he has
four relatively minor
and quite common
mental disorders
that involve
long-standing sadness,
narcissistic self-centeredness,
friendlessness,
an indifference
to the feelings of others.
This is
a very disturbed individual.
But I can't give you any kind
of psychiatric defense for him.
Thank you, Doctor Liu.
Nothing further, Your Honor.
[judge]
Your witness, Ms. Stewart.
Thank you.
Doctor Liu, good morning.
[doctor] Morning.
How long did you interview
Arthur Fleck for?
About two hours.
It was actually 89 minutes.
Tell me,
how can you say for certain,
that Arthur isn't mentally ill?
How can you be so sure
after just 89 minutes,
that this "Joker"
isn't a distinctly separate
and split personality from him?
That that's not who he is.
Well, I also reviewed
all the test results.
Psychological tests,
neurological and medical tests.
And in my view,
it's just a performance.
[crowd murmurs]
[Ms. Stewart]
Did you read the records
from the
Department of Social Services...
...that show that when Arthur
was seven years old,
they returned him
to his abuser's home?
- His mother's home.
- [pen scratching]
[doctor] I did, yes.
[Ms. Stewart] And when you
interviewed him for 89 minutes,
did you ask him
why Social Services
didn't believe
the horrific stories
a seven-year-old boy told them
about the physical
and sexual abuse he suffered?
[faint, echoing laughter]
No, I...
I didn't ask him about that.
[Ms. Stewart] Hmm.
So you want us to believe,
that after spending just
89 minutes with Arthur Fleck,
and reading through
his records and tests
from the same government
agencies that abandoned him,
you want us to believe
that you can say
with absolute certainty
that Arthur doesn't suffer
from any serious mental illness?
That he didn't need
to retreat into fantasy
and create another identity
to protect that scared,
vulnerable, seven-year-old boy
from all the trauma and abuse
he suffered?
And that that identity
didn't come out again,
when he was
attacked and tormented
by three drunk bullies
on the subway?
[three loud, echoing gunshots]
[gun clicking]
"After I woke up this morning,
I thought,
'Murray, Murray, Murray.'
And then there's Murray.
Funny, right?
Then I remember Sophie.
- I had anoth--"
- Objection. Your Honor...
Again, my client's
personal diary is privileged.
[judge] Overruled.
Again, as long as Mrs. Kane
limits her comments
to Mr. Fleck's journals--
But these are my own
personal private jokes.
They weren't meant
to be read out loud.
- Mr. Fleck. Quiet!
- [gavel bangs]
[faint feedback squeal]
[judge] These are your words
she's reading.
And it's up to the jury
to determine
what to make of them.
Please proceed.
Ms. Kane,
please continue reading
from the, uh...
the highlighted portion.
"Then I remember Sophie.
Had another dream about her.
Forgot it.
I almost never dream.
What do I gotta do to remember?"
[Dent] That's Sophie Dumond,
Mr. Fleck's neighbor,
whom he was obsessed with.
What was that date?
November 17.
Let the record show,
November 17th
is the day that Mr. Fleck
stabbed Randall Kleinmanhoffer
to death.
The very same day that he shot
and killed Murray Franklin.
Now, I know it's not
your area of expertise,
but you have read all of
Mr. Fleck's journal before, correct?
[Mrs. Kane] Yes, I have.
And in your opinion,
does this sound
like a different voice?
Like a different, uh...
personality wrote this?
No, it sounds like Arthur.
[Dent] Go on.
He often wrote about
his fantasies.
And... the... women he had
imaginary relationships with.
And of course, his jokes.
There were always
a lot of... these...
these unfunny jokes.
- [crowd laughing]
- [gavel banging]
[Ms. Stewart]
She's just a social worker.
I don't think
she's even qualified--
You know, you're making him out
to be a fucking idiot in there.
[reporters clamoring]
He's never gonna get out
if you keep this shit up.
Ask her why she has me
sitting so far away from him.
Let's not do this here. Please?
Do you see
all those people out front?
Who do you think
they're here for?
How many T-shirts
is Arthur Fleck on?
How many signs?
It's the Trial of the Century
and she doesn't even know
who her own client is.
- What do you mean by that?
- Can't you see how sick he is?
How much help he needs?
He's not sick.
He's perfect.
You don't really think
he's just gonna
walk out of here, do you?
[Lee] Yeah, he's gonna walk
right outta here.
- With me by his side.
- [reporter] And then what?
[reporter 2]
Any further statements?
And then we're gonna
build a mountain.
- [reporter 3] A what?
- From a little hill.
- [reporters clamoring]
- What does that even mean?
- Are you going to get married?
- Move!
[Ms. Stewart]
You're not listening.
We can win this case,
and she's gonna fuck it all up.
No, you're not listening.
Lee's looking out for me.
[helicopter whirring outside]
She understands
what I've been through.
What are you talking about?
We're from
the same neighborhood.
She lost her father. You know...
her mom was awful to her.
She had her committed.
So just give her a break.
Okay, Lee cares about you, sure.
I know.
But she didn't grow up
in your neighborhood.
She lives on the Upper West Side
with her parents.
Her father is not dead,
he's a doctor.
She voluntarily
committed herself
to the hospital,
and then just
checked herself out
when she wanted to.
She didn't check herself out.
Arthur.
I was a bad influence on her,
so they separated us.
Did she mention she went
to grad school for psychiatry?
[giggling] You wouldn't get it.
My point is she's playing you
for a fool.
I'm sorry, I just--
I know what it's like
to love somebody.
But I don't think you can
believe a word she says.
[sighs]
[footsteps retreating]
[door opens, shuts]
[announcer] From NCB Studios
in Gotham City.
Ladies and gentlemen,
it'sThe Joker and Harley Show.
[audience cheering, applauding]
["To Love Somebody" playing]
♪ There's a light ♪
♪ A certain kind of light ♪
♪ That's never shone on me ♪
♪ I want my whole life to be ♪
♪ Lived with you ♪
♪ There's a way ♪
♪ Everybody say ♪
♪ To do each and every
Little thing ♪
♪ But what good does it bring ♪
♪ If I ain't got you ♪
♪ Oh, you don't know
What it's like ♪
♪ Baby, you don't know
♪ To love somebody ♪
♪ The way I love you ♪
♪ Baby, baby, baby, baby ♪
♪ You don't know
What it's like ♪
♪ Baby, you don't know
What it's... ♪
- [music stops]
- [audience murmuring]
What happened?
Well, you weren't even looking
at me anymore.
You were making it
all about yourself.
- [laughter]
- And the song...
[singing] is about loving me!
[cheers, applause]
Now look who's making it
all about themselves.
- [laughter]
- Oh...
So you're saying
it's not about us?
It is, but we're singing
for them.
- [cheers, applause]
- That's why we're here, honey.
Oh! 'Cause I got
this sneaking suspicion
that we're not giving the people
what they want.
It's okay baby, you're right.
Let's give the people
what they want.
[crowd cheering]
Music.
Let's take it from the top.
[song restarts]
[music falters]
Is the honeymoon over?
[people screaming, calling out]
[feedback squealing]
What?
Why'd you-- Why'd you do that?
[audience laughing]
[trumpet playing melody]
[faint prison yard chatter]
Pew!
- [Ricky] Get Healey.
- Pew!
- Ba-room!
- [chuckles]
- [door lock buzzing]
- [door unlatches]
[Jackie] Well, look at you.
Couple of weeks back on TV
and already acting
like you own the joint.
What the fuck are you two doing
sitting on our bleachers?
Who said they're your bleachers?
Ricky, what the fuck
has gotten into you?
[bearded guard]
You heard me. Up.
Guess who I just saw out front?
Your little lady friend.
All right, enough.
Get up, both of you.
[younger guard]
Hey, Fleck, you got a visitor.
See, Arthur? What'd I tell ya?
[older guard] Move it!
[mimics gunshots]
[bearded guard]
Every day, this asshole.
[bearded guard] You're a real
fucking whack job, Fleck.
[older guard] Uh-uh!
[gate clangs shut]
[trumpet continues playing]
[door lock buzzing]
[footsteps approaching]
[Lee] Hey.
[younger guard] Five minutes.
How are you holding up?
[sighs]
[lighter clicks]
Is everything okay?
Did you-- Did you lie to me?
Sure.
I mean, everybody lies a little.
And you're not from
the same neighborhood as me?
[chuckling] And your...
your dad's a doctor?
You're rich?
I just wanted you to like me.
Did you really
check yourself in here?
[chuckling] Yeah.
[giggling]
That's crazy.
Just... because you wanted
to meet me?
Just to meet you.
You could have just
wrote me a letter.
[chuckles]
And said what? I'm nobody.
I haven't done anything
with my life like you have.
Did you really watch
that TV movie
they made about me 20 times?
Um... probably more like
four or five.
[chuckles]
Was it actually good,
or did you lie about that too?
It was great.
[murmurs, exhales]
My lawyer... says you're
playing me for a fool.
I'm no fool.
Can't you see what she's doing?
They're laughing at you
in there.
She doesn't care about you.
I do.
Do you know I moved
into your old apartment building
to make us a home
for when you get out?
- Did your lawyer tell you that?
- [picks up cigarettes]
- You did?
- [lighter clicks]
- I don't want to live there.
- [chuckles]
I'm pregnant.
What?
[Lee] ♪ Why do birds
Suddenly appear ♪
♪ Every time you are near ♪
♪ Just like me ♪
♪ They long to be ♪
♪ Close to you ♪
♪ Why do stars
Fall down from the sky ♪
♪ Every time you walk by ♪
♪ Just like me ♪
♪ They long to be ♪
♪ Close to you ♪
R-Really?
♪ On the day
That you were born ♪
♪ The angels got together ♪
♪ And decided
To make a dream come true ♪
♪ So they sprinkled moon dust
In your hair of gold ♪
♪ And starlight
In your eyes of blue ♪
♪ That is why ♪
- ♪ All the girls in town ♪
- ♪ Girls in town ♪
- ♪ Follow you ♪
- ♪ Follow me ♪
- ♪ All around ♪
♪ Just like me ♪
♪ They long to be ♪
♪ Close to you ♪
[chuckles lightly]
[Lee] ♪ Just like me ♪
♪ They long to be ♪
♪ Close to you ♪
Did you think
he was gonna hurt you?
Or your daughter?
[woman] I did, yes.
You believed he was dangerous.
[woman] Well,
he broke into my apartment.
You call the police?
No.
His mother told me, uh...
that he'd had problems
his whole life, but that he...
wouldn't hurt a fly.
- [dry chuckle]
- [scattered laughter]
And...
...was the man who broke
into your apartment that night,
was he different in any way
from the Arthur Fleck you knew?
I didn't really know him.
I saw him in the lobby,
the elevator a few times.
Like I said,
I knew his mother a little bit.
She was really sweet
to my daughter.
[Dent] And Ms. Dumond,
why is it that you didn't want
to come here and testify today?
And why did you initially
ignore our subpoenas?
Well,
after Arthur did what he did,
the press wanted
to talk to me about it.
And then I was a character
in that awful TV movie
they made, and...
- [whispers] It was awful?
- Then all these people...
No.
...supporters, I guess,
like the people outside,
started showing up
at my work and harassing me,
blaming me for what happened
to Arthur.
So I was afraid for my safety
and for my daughter's safety.
We moved out of the city.
Well, then why did you
finally decide to comply?
Because I should have
called the police that night.
Then maybe all those people
wouldn't have been...
Maybe they wouldn't be
dead now if I did.
Thank you. No more questions.
[judge]
Your witness, Ms. Stewart.
[Ms. Stewart] Ms. Dumond.
What happened
after you asked Arthur
to leave your apartment
that night?
He told me he was having
a bad day. And then he left.
So, he never hurt
or even threatened
you or your daughter?
[Sophie] No.
And did you watch him on TV
on Murray Franklin
the following week?
[Sophie] I did.
[Ms. Stewart] And did that seem
like the same man
who was sitting
in your apartment that night?
Did he sound the same
or even look the same?
No, I mean, he was...
he was wearing clown make-up.
[laughter]
[Ms. Stewart]
And while Arthur's mother
was being so sweet
to your daughter,
what was she telling you
about her own son?
Um...
She told me that there was
something wrong with Arthur,
and that he lived
in a fantasy world
and that he had this laugh.
[Ms. Stewart] She told you
it was a "dumb laugh."
That's what she called it.
"His dumb laugh."
[Sophie] Yes.
[Ms. Stewart]
What else did she tell you?
That she made up a story,
when he was a kid.
So that he would feel
better about it.
So that he would stop crying,
so that he wouldn't
kill himself.
What was the story?
[Sophie] That he was put
on this earth to bring joy.
Something like that.
It's why she called him "Happy."
[Ms. Stewart] And?
[Sophie] And she...
couldn't believe that
he based his whole life
around this made-up story.
He was a street clown,
and he wanted to be a comedian.
[laughter]
[Ms. Stewart]
She made fun of him
for doing that?
[Sophie] She just thought
it was ridiculous
that he thought
he could make people laugh.
I mean, she said Arthur
wasn't funny at all.
- [laughter]
- [voices fading]
[Ms. Stewart] Did she tell you
that he had been
in and out of institutions
his whole life?
[Sophie] Yes.
[Ms. Stewart] Did she say
anything else about him?
♪ There's always a joker ♪
♪ In the pack ♪
♪ There's always
A lonely clown ♪
♪ The poor laughing fool
Falls on his back ♪
♪ And everyone laughs
When he's down ♪
♪ There's always a funny man ♪
♪ In the game ♪
♪ But he's only funny
By mistake ♪
♪ And everyone looks at him ♪
♪ Just the same ♪
♪ They don't see
His lonely heart break ♪
- [grunts explosively]
- [crowd exclaiming]
[stool clatters]
- [microphone thuds]
- [feedback squeals]
♪ They don't care
As long as there is a jester ♪
♪ Just a fool ♪
♪ As foolish as he can be ♪
♪ There's always a joker ♪
♪ That's the rule ♪
♪ But fate deals the hand
And I see ♪
♪ The joker is me ♪
[crowd applauding]
[smart, jazzy interlude playing]
♪ They don't care as long as ♪
- ♪ There is a jester ♪
- [jury exclaiming]
♪ Just a fool ♪
♪ As foolish as he can be ♪
- [gun booms]
- ♪ There's always a joker ♪
♪ That's the rule! ♪
♪ But fate deals a hand
And I see ♪
♪ The joker is me ♪
[people exclaiming]
- [gavel thudding]
- [crowd murmuring, chuckling]
[panting]
[gavel clattering]
♪ The joker ♪
♪ Is me ♪
- [gunshot echoes]
- [song ends]
[Sophie] Yeah.
That he had never had
a girlfriend
and she thought
he was probably a virgin.
I can't do this.
- Oh! I can't do this anymore!
- [gavel banging]
Your Honor, may I approach
the bench, please?
[judge] No, you may not.
I want to fire my lawyer.
[man in audience]
It's about time!
Excuse me?
- I'd like to represent myself.
- [applause]
You're fired.
Arthur, don't do this.
This is real.
- You'd better believe it's real.
- [gavel banging]
[judge]
I want order in my court. Order!
[crowd cheering]
Bailiff! Take Mr. Fleck
to his holding cell!
[judge] Order!
I want to see all counsel
in my chambers immediately!
- [people cheering]
- [gavel rapping loudly]
This way? Thank you.
Hey, no touching.
I'm so fucking proud of you.
You should see it out there.
They're all going crazy for you.
You did it.
I know, but maybe I should read
a law book or something.
You know I never went
to high school?
[both laughing]
[cell guard]
I said, no touching.
You can do anything you want.
You're Joker.
[cigarette crackling]
[radio news fanfare playing]
[man on radio] Good evening,
it's 48 degrees at 6:00
on this Wednesday,
November 8th.
I'm Stan L. Brooks
and here's what's happening.
Shocking developments
at the trial
of Arthur Fleck downtown today.
Fleck, the accused killer,
also known as Joker,
interrupted testimony
and fired his lawyer
Maryanne Stewart in open court.
Then he kissed her goodbye.
Afterwards, Fleck
was extensively questioned
by Judge Herman Rothwax.
[judge] The right
of self-representation
is not a license to abuse
the dignity of the courtroom.
Can you control your emotions,
Mr. Fleck?
[Arthur] Yes, sir.
[Brooks]
Judge Rothwax reluctantly
approved Fleck's request
to represent himself,
as long as he agreed
to stand-by counsel.
A decision that both Fleck's
now former attorney,
Maryanne Stewart
and Assistant DA, Harvey Dent
disagree with.
[Ms. Stewart]
It's really tragic.
Arthur believes he has
all of these supporters,
but they don't care about him.
They care about Joker.
[continues on television]
He's not dealing with reality.
He's mentally ill.
If we could have
just convinced him of that
then we would have won
this case.
[Dent]
Fleck knows what he's doing.
He knows he's losing.
We cannot forget
that he's evil.
This is all just
part of his plan.
[Brooks] The Arthur Fleck trial
will resume on Monday morning.
In other news,
Mayor Thorndike...
[cups banging on tables]
- [Bullock] There he is.
- [inmates cheering]
[younger guard]
All right, calm down, everybody.
[bearded guard]
Hey, shut the fuck up!
Sit down. Sit down.
- Fleck, get off. Arthur!
- [Bullock] Yeah, Arthur!
[younger guard]
Hey, come on. Get off the table.
[older guard] Get down, Arthur.
- ♪ Oh, when the saints ♪
- Sit the fuck down, Ricky.
- ♪ Go marching in ♪
- Ricky!
♪ Oh, when the saints
Go marching in ♪
Ricky! Get the fuck down.
♪ Oh Lord
I want to be in that number ♪
- [Jackie] Give me the hat!
- ♪ When the saints-- ♪
Get the fuck down
when I tell ya.
[inmates clamoring]
[bearded guard]
Finish your fucking dinner.
Sit down!
- Calm it down.
- All right, show's over.
Calm down.
- [all shouting, clamoring]
- Sit the fuck down!
♪ When the saints
Go marching in ♪
- Bullock!
- ♪ Oh, when the saints! ♪
♪ Go marching in! ♪
[all] ♪ Oh, when the saints
Go marching in ♪
♪ Oh, Lord
I want to be in that number ♪
[alarm clanging]
♪ When the saints
Go marching in ♪
[singing, noises fade]
[cackling]
[bearded guard]
I'll crack your skull open.
[singing, shouting]
[laughter echoing]
[fading] ♪ When the saints
Go marching in ♪
After reviewing all the case law
that offers precedent,
Jensen v. Superior Court
being the most relevant,
I have reluctantly decided
that Mr. Fleck
does have the right
as an attorney,
to dress himself how he likes...
[loud cheer]
...as long as he doesn't
cause disorder
or interfere with
the functioning of the Court.
I will not allow
this proceeding
to become as unruly
as it is outside.
And I will not let you
turn this into
any more of a circus
than you already have.
- [scattered laughter]
- Thank you.
[judge] Mr. Dent,
call your next witness.
The State calls Gary Puddles.
Bailiff?
Will you please escort
Mr. Puddles to the stand?
[short chuckle]
[door opens]
[quiet, murmured laughter]
Gary.
Go get 'em. [chuckles lightly]
[bailiff]
Please raise your right hand.
Do you solemnly swear
that the testimony
you're about to give
is the whole truth
and nothing but the truth,
so help you God?
[British accent] I do.
[Dent]
Good morning, Mr. Puddles.
- [light chuckle]
- Thank you for being here.
[Dent]
So one last question, sir.
The person who you saw
stab Randall Kleinmanhoffer
to death,
are they in this courtroom
here today?
Yes.
Can you point him out
to all of us?
And... describe his clothing?
He's... He's sitting right there
at the table.
Wearing a red suit
and clown make-up.
- [laughter]
- [Dent] May the record reflect
the identification
of the accused, Your Honor?
[judge] Yes, it will.
Nothing further, Your Honor.
[judge] Your witness, Mr. Fleck.
[sighing deeply]
[Southern accent] Mr. Puddles.
Gary Puddles?
Tell me, sir,
is that your God-given name?
Yes.
Really?
[normal voice] Really?
Your last name is Puddles?
[scoffing chuckle]
[Southern accent]
Why, it sounds like a... a joke.
Well, it's not.
[normal voice]
You expect us to believe
that your last name is Puddles?
- Puddles?
- [laughter]
Mr. Fleck, where is this going?
As I said, I'm not gonna let you
turn my courtroom into a circus.
Okay.
But, um, with all due respect,
Your Honor,
don't you think
it's a little late for that?
- Don't try my patience.
- [Arthur] Okay. Okay.
[clears throat]
[Southern accent] Mr. Puddles...
earlier this afternoon
you testified
that you saw me stab
Mr. Kliman Manhoff
in the neck a couple of times.
Correct?
Kleinmanhoffer.
Yes, I saw you.
Mm.
And what else
did you see that day?
[voice shaking]
You stabbing him in the eye,
and bashing his head
into the wall,
many, many times.
Yes, but, uh, Randall
was a bit of a bully, wasn't he?
He didn't deserve to die.
- I don't know.
- [scattered chuckling]
Eh, never mind.
Gary, did you catch my act
on The Murray Franklin Show
later that night?
No, I didn't.
No?
Might I remind you
that you are under oath?
I was locked up
at the police station.
In an interview room.
'Cause they thought
you might come and kill me.
I was the only witness.
They kept me in there all night.
Isn't that convenient,
Mr. Puddles?
That you didn't see the show,
you didn't see anything
I had to say,
[normal voice]
I can't believe it!
Mr. Fleck.
Okay. [clears throat]
[Southern accent]
Uh, when you were
in my mama's apartment,
God rest her soul,
when, as you say, you saw me
bash Mr. Klannonmen--
whatever's-- head into the wall,
"many, many times,"
did I seem crazy to you?
Did I seem
like a different person?
Or was I the same old Joker
that I always been?
Arthur, don't do this
to yourself, it isn't you.
[imitating accent] It isn't me?
So you don't think this is me?
Well, maybe... maybe...
you don't know who I really was.
I never saw that side of you.
[Southern accent]
Well, maybe you weren't looking.
Maybe no one was.
Because nobody knew I existed.
But look around,
look at all these people.
Everyone outside. These cameras.
Who do you think they see,
Mr. Puddles?
[sniffling] Joker.
Oh, sweet child,
what you have proven here today,
is that you are no different
than any of those people
that underestimated me.
[normal voice]
From Murray Franklin,
to those goddamn fat,
stupid guards at Arkham.
They think that
they can treat me like trash.
But I will no longer allow you,
or you, or you,
or any of you to keep me down.
- I am free!
- [crowd chattering]
[all cheering]
[Gary] Why are you doing this
to me, Arthur?
What?
Gary, I like you.
I told you I wouldn't hurt you,
and I didn't.
Not hurt me?
[crying softly]
I couldn't go back to work.
I still can't sleep,
and I'm scared all the time.
I never used to be scared.
I'm scared right now, here.
With you in front of me.
I couldn't do anything that day.
I felt so small.
[sniffles] I was reminded
how powerless I really am.
[Southern accent] Oh... you got
a flair for the dramatic.
You are tugging at
my heart strings, little Gary.
No more-- no more questions,
Your Honor.
Do you know
what that feels like, Arthur?
[under breath] Oh, fuck!
You were the only one at work
who never made fun of me.
You were the only one
that was nice to me.
[Gary crying]
I said, no more questions,
Your Honor!
[Gary sniffling]
[judge] Very well, Mr. Puddles.
The court thanks you
for your testimony.
Please step down,
you're excused.
[judge] Mr. Dent,
call your next witness.
We're not calling
any more witnesses, Your Honor.
That is the State's case.
The State rests.
[judge] Very well.
All right, Mr. Fleck,
at this point,
you may mount your defense.
[clicks teeth]
The defense rests as well,
Your Honor.
[excited murmuring in crowd]
[judge] Pardon?
Mr. Fleck, you don't want
to put on any defense?
No, Your Honor.
The defense rests.
"Th-Th-Th-That's all folks."
- [crowd cheering]
- [judge] All right, all right.
[gavel banging]
All right.
[judge] That's enough!
This is a court of law!
With both sides having rested,
this court will recess
until tomorrow morning at 9:30.
[man] You made our case
for us, you fucking idiot!
[man 2] You're gonna fry
for killing my son!
[man 3] Burn in hell!
[reporter]
Anything you want to say?
[reporter 2]
Arthur, will you be convicted?
[photographer]
Arthur, over here.
[photographer 2]
Let's see that smile.
Where do you think you stand,
Arthur?
- [crowd murmuring]
- [cameras clicking]
[reporter] What are you
gonna do if they let you off?
[organ playing melody]
♪ We're gonna
Build a mountain ♪
♪ From a little hill ♪
♪ Gonna build me a mountain ♪
♪ Least I hope I will ♪
♪ Gonna build a mountain ♪
♪ Gonna build it high ♪
[door kicks open]
♪ I don't know
How we're gonna do it ♪
♪ Only know we're gonna try ♪
[upbeat, jazzy music playing]
♪ Gonna build us a heaven ♪
♪ From a little hell ♪
♪ And I know darn well ♪
♪ That if I build
That mountain ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
- ♪ With a lot of care ♪
♪ I'll take our daydream
Up the mountain ♪
♪ And heaven
Will be waiting there ♪
♪ I'm gonna build a mountain ♪
♪ From a little heaven ♪
Do you?
I do.
And you?
- ♪ Oh, yeah ♪
- ♪ Look at that mountain ♪
♪ Look at that mountain ♪
- ♪ Gonna build a mountain ♪
♪ Gonna build a mountain ♪
♪ Oh, let me build it ♪
♪ Just one mountain high ♪
♪ Gonna build a mountain
With a lot of care ♪
♪ I'll take my daydream
Up the mountain ♪
♪ And heaven
Will be waiting there ♪
[tap shoes
clicking complex rhythm]
[audience cheering]
♪ Gonna build ♪
♪ I'm gonna build us ♪
♪ I'm gonna build us
A mountain ♪
♪ Build us a mountain ♪
♪ High, let's build it ♪
♪ Mountain, mountain
Build a mountain ♪
♪ Mountain, mountain ♪
[crowd cheering, whistling]
[applause fading]
["Dancing in the Moonlight" by
King Harvest playing on radio]
[driver] I told him,
"I'm not dealing
with those days."
I'm only working
four of these days.
[driver 2] Good for you.
[song continues]
[gate lock buzzes]
[motor shuts off]
[door lock buzzes]
[faint shouts and chatter]
Joe, how goes it?
You know, same old bullshit.
[inmate] Joker.
[younger guard] How's Kathy?
[inmate 2] Is that really him?
[Joe] Still busting my balls.
[younger guard]
Yeah, they always do.
Yep.
See you fellas in the morning.
[inmate whistling]
[inmate] Give 'em hell, man.
[Arthur] Uh-oh.
I'm in trouble.
What?
Move.
Easy, darling.
[Arthur] Why is everyone
so upset with me?
[Jackie] Move your ass.
[Arthur laughing]
Come on, Arthur.
[grunts]
[Arthur] I'm an attorney now!
- I will see you in court.
- Shut the fuck up.
And I'm the fucking
Queen of Sheba.
I'm gonna fucking murder you.
[grunts]
[younger guard] Yeah?
Get up!
[Jackie] Grab his legs, Mac.
[Mac] Let's go.
[Jackie] Had to go and be
a big shot on TV.
[Mac]
I think he knocked himself out.
[Mac] Motherfucker.
Stand him up.
[grunting]
All right, I get it.
I get it, Jackie.
You wanna--
You wanna hear a joke, right?
- You really think...
- [spluttering]
...fancy red suit
and muck on your face
makes you better than us?
You have no fucking idea
what it takes,
put a little bit of joy
into this fucking place.
Let me tell you one I used to do
about my mother.
You can drop the act now.
- My mother was...
- Because we know
it's only Arthur in there, okay?
[panting]
And she only dated abusive guys.
Yeah, is that right?
And, I asked her, I said,
"Mom, why do you stay
with your abusive boyfriend?"
And she said...
[high voice]
"Beats the hell out of me."
[laughing loudly]
[Jackie] I told you to drop it.
Oh, he liked it!
[feminine voice] Oh, Jackie...
aren't you gonna
buy me a drink first?
[Jackie] Let's go, let's go.
- Let's fucking go!
- [Arthur] No!
[whimpering]
- Get the fuck in there!
- No!
- Let go!
- Get that fucking jacket off.
[Mac] Shut the fuck up.
Get his fucking rags off.
[Arthur] Jackie!
No! No!
- [pounding door]
- [Bullock] Arthur!
[Mac]
Mind your business, Bullock!
[Ricky] What'd you do to him?
[Jackie]
Shut the fuck up, Ricky!
[Bullock] What happened, Arthur?
[Ricky]
The saints are coming, Jackie!
The saints are coming!
[Ricky] ♪ Oh, when the saints
Oh, when the saints ♪
♪ Oh, when the saints
Go marching in ♪
[Jackie] Shut the fuck up!
♪ Oh, Lord
I want to be in that number ♪
[Jackie]
Get him fucking out of there!
♪ When the saints
Go marching in ♪
No, no! No! [grunts]
Come here, damn it.
[Ricky choking]
[Jackie]
Fucking coming now, are they?
- Fucking asshole.
- [Ricky gasping, choking]
[Jackie] Are they coming now?
[Mac] Ease up, Jackie.
Let him go, he can't breathe.
[Jackie]
I told you to shut the fuck up.
[Bullock] Leave him alone.
[Jackie] Shut... the fuck...
- [Mac] Jackie, take it easy.
- [Jackie] ...up!
[Ricky gags]
[Jackie grunts]
[body thuds]
[Jackie panting]
[Mac] He's gone.
[water running]
[light fixture buzzing]
[Lee] ♪ I've got the world
On a string ♪
♪ Sittin' on a rainbow ♪
♪ Got that string
Around my finger ♪
♪ What a world, what a life ♪
♪ I'm in love ♪
♪ I've got a song that I sing ♪
♪ I can make the rain go ♪
♪ Anytime I move my finger ♪
♪ Lucky me ♪
♪ Can't you see, I'm in love ♪
♪ Life is a beautiful thing ♪
♪ As long as
I hold that string ♪
♪ I'd be a silly so and so ♪
♪ If I should ever let it go ♪
♪ I've got the world
On a string ♪
♪ And I'm sittin'
On a rainbow ♪
♪ Got that string
Around my finger ♪
♪ What a world ♪
♪ Yeah, there ain't no other
Kind of life ♪
♪ What a world, what a life ♪
♪ Hey now, I'm so in love ♪
[judge] Mr. Fleck,
your closing statement.
[feedback squeals]
[murmuring laughter]
A word of caution.
This is not a comedy club.
You are not onstage.
[laughter]
[judge] Excuse me.
Do you need a short recess, sir?
[exhales slowly]
[smacks lips]
I... I wanted to come out here
as Joker.
And I was gonna go on a...
an angry rant.
[voice trembling]
And blame all of you,
and everyone...
[breath shaking]
...for this
fucking miserable life.
[sniffles]
But it wouldn't matter,
because I can't do this
anymore.
'Cause I can't be
who you want me to be.
It was all just a fantasy.
[shuddering sigh]
There is no Joker.
[faint murmuring in crowd]
It's just me.
[hushed whispering]
I-I killed six people.
I wish I didn't, but I did.
[sniffles]
Nobody knows, but...
I also killed my mother.
[sniffs]
Put a... pillow over her face,
and smothered her to death.
[shocked murmuring]
I just wanna...
I just wanna blow it all up,
and start a new life.
[doors open]
[gavel rapping]
[judge] Settle down.
[sobs]
- [feedback whines]
- [sniffles]
[voice faltering]
Knock... knock.
Who's there?
Arthur Fleck.
Arthur Fleck who?
[line ringing]
[Lee] Hey, it's Harley,
leave a message at the beep.
Unless you're a reporter,
in which case
you can just fuck off.
Thanks.
[machine beeps]
Hi, it's me. Arthur.
[faint crowd noise from outside]
The jury has already
come back with a verdict.
Took 'em less than an hour.
So, you know.
But they let me call you
to see if you'd come back,
'cause I want you here.
I didn't want you to go.
♪ If you go away ♪
♪ On this sunny day ♪
♪ Then you might as well
Take the sun away ♪
♪ All the birds that flew ♪
♪ In the bright blue sky ♪
♪ When our love was new ♪
♪ And our hearts were high ♪
♪ And the day was young ♪
♪ And the night was long ♪
♪ And the moon stood still ♪
♪ For the night bird's song ♪
♪ If you go away ♪
♪ But if you stay
I'll make you a day ♪
♪ Like no day has been
Or will be again ♪
♪ We'll ride on the rain ♪
♪ We'll sail on your touch ♪
♪ I'll talk to your eyes
That I love so much ♪
♪ And if you go
Go, I won't cry ♪
♪ All the good is gone ♪
♪ From the word goodbye ♪
♪ If you go away ♪
♪ Ne me quitte pas ♪
[reporter] Tension is mounting
as we wait to hear the verdict
in the trial of Arthur Fleck.
♪ If you go away ♪
♪ As I know you must ♪
♪ There'll be nothing left ♪
♪ In the world to trust ♪
♪ Just an empty room ♪
♪ Full of empty space ♪
♪ Like the empty look ♪
♪ I see on your face ♪
♪ I'd have been the shadow
Of your dog ♪
♪ If I'd thought it ♪
♪ Might have kept me
By your side ♪
[machine beeps]
♪ If you go away ♪
As a reminder,
regardless of the verdict,
I will not tolerate
any outbursts of any kind.
Foreperson, you may begin.
In the matter of The People
of the State of New York
versus Arthur Fleck,
case number GC071963.
As to count one, we, the jury,
find Arthur Fleck
guilty as charged,
with Murder in the First Degree
- against Maurice Franklin.
- [people clamoring]
So say we all.
As to count two,
we, the jury, find Arthur Fleck
guilty as charged,
with Murder in the Second Degree
against Randall Kleinmanhoffer.
- So say we all.
- [chuckling]
- As to count three...
- [laughing]
...we, the jury,
find Arthur Fleck...
guilty as charged...
- Stop laughing, you sick fuck!
- [people screaming]
- [Arthur laughing]
- [people shouting]
[man] Fucking son of a bitch.
[continues shouting]
Sit down!
All of you will be held
in contempt.
Bailiffs, get them
out of here immediately.
[laughing]
- [judge] Get them out of here.
- Don't move.
- You sick fuck.
- [gavel banging]
[sound muted]
[muffled moan]
[high-pitched ringing]
[faint, muffled breathing]
[coughing, muffled]
[muffled grunts]
[faint, muffled] It's you.
[inaudible]
Come on, man. We gotta get you
the fuck outta here.
Come on.
[muffled, inaudible speech]
I'll get somebody.
[Joker fan, faintly] Hey! Hey!
I got the fucking Joker.
Can you get us outta here?
[driver] Yeah, get him in.
Get in. Get in, get in.
["My Life" by Billy Joel
playing faintly]
[driver]
Holy shit, it's really him.
Where's he wanna go?
[Joker fan]
Drive. Just fucking go.
Those motherfuckers
got what they deserved.
[driver] Where does he wanna go?
Where should we go?
[Joker fan] Just get us
the fuck outta here, man.
Hey, get down. Stay down.
- [normal sounds return]
- [Joker fan] Get down, man.
Can you go any
fucking faster, man? Come on.
[driver] I'm trying. Fuck!
There's cops everywhere.
[Joker fan] You did it, man.
You fucking did it!
[Joker fan] You said you wanted
to blow it all up.
And somebody
blew it the fuck up!
[driver cackling]
This is fucking crazy!
Fuck you.
[driver] Fuck you. [laughs]
Whooo!
[man on radio]
We have devastating news
to report, right now.
A massive car bomb has gone off
in downtown Gotham.
- [Joker fan] Holy shit.
- Exploding just outside
the county courthouse...
- [driver] Oh, my God.
- ...where thousands
had turned out
to hear the verdict
in the Arthur Fleck trial.
Details are still coming in.
- Continue to stay tuned...
- [Joker fan] You okay?
...as we bring you
the latest...
[Joker fan] You hurt?
- ...on this situation.
- [Joker fan] Are you okay, man?
[driver] Is he all right?
["My Life" resumes on radio]
[Joker fan] Fuck. Fucking A.
Can you cut around it?
[driver] No, chill out,
it's red. It's okay.
- Fuck!
- Calm down, man.
[Joker fan] This is just
the beginning, man.
They're gonna burn
the whole fucking city down now.
[laughs maniacally]
[Joker fan] No, no. Wait.
Wait, don't do this, man.
[driver] Come on, man.
Get back inside.
- [Joker fan] Get in. Get in.
- [horns blaring]
[sirens wailing]
- [Joker fan] Hey, hey, hey!
- [driver] Come back!
- Come back, man. Joker.
- [sirens approaching]
- [Joker fan] Fuck.
- [Arthur panting]
- [siren whoops]
- [Joker fan] No!
Where are you going, man?
We still love you.
We love you, Joker.
Joker!
- [helicopter whirring]
- [sirens wailing]
[Joker fan] Joker!
[sirens wailing in distance]
[car horn blaring]
Lee?
[dogs barking faintly]
Lee!
[panting]
Look at you.
You cut your hair.
Someone blew up the courthouse,
and I'm free.
We can go away.
Lee, you hear me?
Someone blew up the courthouse.
We can go.
I escaped.
We're not going away, Arthur.
All we had was the fantasy,
and you gave up.
We were never going anywhere.
I'm that same guy
you fell in love with.
I'm the same guy
that murdered Murray Franklin.
No.
No, you're not.
There is no Joker.
That's what you said, isn't it?
[stammers]
I can't--
I can't live without you.
Please. We're having a baby.
♪ A show
That is really a show ♪
♪ Sends you out ♪
Please stop.
♪ With a kind of a glow
And you'll say ♪
♪ As you go on your way ♪
♪ That's entertainment ♪
I don't wanna sing anymore.
♪ A song ♪
Shh.
♪ That is winging along ♪
- Just talk to me.
- ♪ Or a dance ♪
♪ With a touch of romance ♪
Just talk. Please stop singing.
♪ You believe ♪
♪ In all that we had dreamed ♪
♪ That's entertainment ♪
[sirens approaching]
Goodbye, Arthur.
[sirens wailing]
[car doors shutting]
[thunder rumbling]
Touching, is it not?
Come,
my little peanut of brittle.
I will help you.
[inmates laughing]
[Jackie singing, indistinct]
♪ We're not a crowd... ♪
[inmate laughing]
[Jackie] ♪ My echo
My shadow and me ♪
Fleck.
Let's go, you got a visitor.
[bearded guard]
No fucking cigarettes left.
[guards chattering indistinctly]
[older guard] Let's go.
[whistling "When the Saints
Go Marching In"]
Hey, Arthur. Hold up.
Can I tell you a joke
I came up with?
Um...
Is it quick?
Yeah, I can make it quick.
Okay.
So, a psychopath walks
into a bar,
and sees this famous clown
sitting there all alone.
Totally drunk, it's pathetic.
"I can't believe you're here,"
he says.
"What a disappointment.
I used to watch you on TV.
What can I get you?"
And this clown turns and says,
"Well, if you're buying
you can get me anything."
"Perfect," the psychopath says.
"How about I get you
what you fucking deserve?"
- [knife plunges]
- [cries out]
[groaning in pain]
[psychopath laughing]
[Arthur groaning]
[audience laughing]
- [applause swelling]
- [crowd cheering]
[man in audience] Yeah!
♪ Whe... When... ♪
♪ When I build that mountain ♪
♪ As I will someday ♪
♪ And the Lord sends Gabriel ♪
♪ To take me away ♪
♪ I want a fine young son ♪
♪ To take my place ♪
♪ I'll leave a son ♪
♪ In my heaven on earth ♪
♪ With the good Lord's... ♪
- [Arthur groans]
- [cackling]
♪ ...grace ♪
[laughing]
[thunder rumbles faintly]
["That's Life"
by Lady Gaga playing]
[panting]
[knife slicing flesh]
[psychopath whimpering, moaning]
[psychopath cackling]
["True Love Will Find You
in the End" playing]